<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home of Srđan Đukić</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/</link><description>Recent content on Home of Srđan Đukić</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 21:59:32 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://srdan.geek.nz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docker Container image scanning</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/wednesday-29th-sept/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 21:59:32 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/wednesday-29th-sept/</guid><description>Docker Container image scanning Some time ago, I wrote an article talking about the state of container scanning as it became clear that container images were going to have to be patched and the process was going to have to be managed just the same as we do for Linux boxes.
Recently, the question came up again at work after a colleague rightly balked at the integrated Azure Container Registry option (Azure Defender for ACR) costing ~$0.</description></item><item><title>The rise of K8s for infrastructure management</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/tuesday-28th-sept/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 22:01:55 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/tuesday-28th-sept/</guid><description>The rise of K8s for infrastructure management One of the typically overlooked aspects of moving to microservice architecture in general (and specificallyK8s for the purposes of this article) is the fact that each service &amp;ldquo;owns&amp;rdquo; its own datastore. Unless constrained by costs, this means a fully managed datastore instance (e.g. RDS). Once we accept that the service owns and manages the creation, upgrades etc&amp;hellip; of its own datastore, it then becomes logical to store the &amp;ldquo;infrastructure code&amp;rdquo; for this next to the application code (i.</description></item><item><title>My Second Post</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/my-second-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 22:36:10 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/my-second-post/</guid><description>Second Post Hi Again. Trying out the GitHub Actions triggers to rebuild and publish Hugo to the correct branch.</description></item><item><title>My first post</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 21:58:46 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>Hello World! Hi! This is my first blog post.</description></item></channel></rss>