<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>authentication on Home of Srđan Đukić</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/tags/authentication/</link><description>Recent content in authentication on Home of Srđan Đukić</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:48:56 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://srdan.geek.nz/tags/authentication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up Mutual TLS with Prometheus</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-15th-july-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:48:56 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-15th-july-22/</guid><description>About Link to heading So, recently I was tasked with trying to securely enable metrics collection from servers which did not have a private/management IP, only a publicly routable IP address.
This was a challenge in that if we are going to expose metrics over the public internet, security becomes a much bigger focus.
While it was tempting to rely on a single mechanism to restrict access (such as firewall rules to only allow connections from the Prometheus server), experience has taught us that it&amp;rsquo;s much better to not assume that any single mechanism will work all the time (see: Swiss Cheese Model).</description></item><item><title>Creating SSHFP records</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/monday-1st-february-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 11:32:46 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/monday-1st-february-22/</guid><description>How to setup SSHFP records to verify SSH fingerprints Link to heading What are SSHFP records and what problem are we trying to solve? Link to heading NOTE: Feel free to skip this part if you know what SSHFP records are and want to get to the instructions
So, you might have noticed that every time you connect to a server over SSH you get a message like this:</description></item></channel></rss>