<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tls on Home of Srđan Đukić</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/tags/tls/</link><description>Recent content in Tls on Home of Srđan Đukić</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:48:56 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://srdan.geek.nz/tags/tls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up Mutual TLS with Prometheus</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-15th-july-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:48:56 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-15th-july-22/</guid><description>About Link to heading So, recently I was tasked with trying to securely enable metrics collection from servers which did not have a private/management IP, only a publicly routable IP address.
This was a challenge in that if we are going to expose metrics over the public internet, security becomes a much bigger focus.
While it was tempting to rely on a single mechanism to restrict access (such as firewall rules to only allow connections from the Prometheus server), experience has taught us that it&amp;rsquo;s much better to not assume that any single mechanism will work all the time (see: Swiss Cheese Model).</description></item><item><title>Generating CA and certificates with CFSSL</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/thursday-14th-july-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:08:24 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/thursday-14th-july-22/</guid><description>Generating a CA and signing certificates with CFSSL Link to heading About Link to heading Background Link to heading Recently I was trying to setup an example mutual TLS configuration between Prometheus (the server) and Node Exporter. In doing so I used OpenSSL to generate a CA and certificates for Prometheus and then have the Node exporter trust any client certificates signed by the CA.
It took a long time to generate the CA and sign the certs, mostly due to having to figure out the openssl command line syntax and flags etc&amp;hellip; eventually I got there, only to hit this issue:</description></item></channel></rss>