<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Home of Srđan Đukić</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Home of Srđan Đukić</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 15:21:18 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zenva Object Oriented C++ course</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/wednesday-23rd-november/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 15:21:18 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/wednesday-23rd-november/</guid><description>Zenva Learn Object-Oriented C++ by Building a Game A while ago I bought a bunch of Zenva programming courses from Humble Bundle as some of the courses covered C++, which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t touched since university, but was becoming a language that I was dealing with semi frequently in my new role.
So, this was a &amp;ldquo;refresher&amp;rdquo; on the C++ world and where it had come to in the last 10 years or.</description></item><item><title>Friday 12th August 22</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-12th-august-22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 10:19:26 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-12th-august-22/</guid><description>HackerRank electronics shop problem: func getMoneySpent(keyboards []int32, drives []int32, b int32) int32 { maxSpend := -1 for _, k := range(keyboards){ for _, d := range(drives){ price := int(k + d) if price &amp;lt;= int(b) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; price &amp;gt; maxSpend { maxSpend = price } } } return int32(maxSpend) } Surprisingly got this on the first go. HackerRank using &amp;ldquo;int32&amp;rdquo; everywhere is annoying as it means typecasting all over the place</description></item><item><title>Thursday and daily blogging</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/thursday-11th-august-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 11:21:35 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/thursday-11th-august-22/</guid><description>A random Thursday in August So, in order to try and slay my own demons of procrastination and a general feeling of not achieving anything, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start blogging regularly about all the big and small achievements every day.
Today I:
Solved two basic HackerRank exercises: Drawing Book func pageCount(n int32, p int32) int32 { numBuckets := n/2 bucketNumber := p/2 wayFromBack := numBuckets - bucketNumber if (bucketNumber &amp;lt; wayFromBack){ return bucketNumber } else { return wayFromBack } } Which was surprisingly easy in the end, but for some reason I massively over-thought it when I first looked at it.</description></item><item><title>Setting up Mutual TLS with Prometheus</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-15th-july-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:48:56 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-15th-july-22/</guid><description>About So, recently I was tasked with trying to securely enable metrics collection from servers which did not have a private/management IP, only a publicly routable IP address.
This was a challenge in that if we are going to expose metrics over the public internet, security becomes a much bigger focus.
While it was tempting to rely on a single mechanism to restrict access (such as firewall rules to only allow connections from the Prometheus server), experience has taught us that it&amp;rsquo;s much better to not assume that any single mechanism will work all the time (see: Swiss Cheese Model).</description></item><item><title>Generating CA and certificates with CFSSL</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/thursday-14th-july-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:08:24 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/thursday-14th-july-22/</guid><description>Generating a CA and signing certificates with CFSSL About Background Recently I was trying to setup an example mutual TLS configuration between Prometheus (the server) and Node Exporter. In doing so I used OpenSSL to generate a CA and certificates for Prometheus and then have the Node exporter trust any client certificates signed by the CA.
It took a long time to generate the CA and sign the certs, mostly due to having to figure out the openssl command line syntax and flags etc&amp;hellip; eventually I got there, only to hit this issue:</description></item><item><title>Read the requirements carefully</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/tuesday-21st-june-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 09:21:11 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/tuesday-21st-june-22/</guid><description>Reading the requirements So, last night I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep and decided to hop onto hackerrank.com and have a go at attempting the divisible sum pairs problem:
Given an array of integers and a positive integer k, determine the number of (i, j) pairs where i &amp;lt; j and ar[i] + ar[j] is divisible by k.
It looked fairly straight forward and in fact I was pretty sure that I had attempted a problem like it previously.</description></item><item><title>Docker install in 2022</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-13th-may/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 16:05:14 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-13th-may/</guid><description>#How to Install Docker in 2022
So, assuming that you only need the CLI, don&amp;rsquo;t need the K8s, you should just follow the guide here:
https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/ubuntu/
Avoid the snap as it has issues with outbound access from running containers.</description></item><item><title>Adding Ansible syntax highlighting to Vim</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/monday-14th-february-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 15:28:40 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/monday-14th-february-22/</guid><description>How to add Ansible playbook syntax highlighting to Vim After a lot of trying out different Vim plugins to try and find one that works, it seems that:
https://github.com/pearofducks/ansible-vim
was the only plugin that worked out of all the ones I tried.</description></item><item><title>Creating SSHFP records</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/monday-1st-february-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 11:32:46 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/monday-1st-february-22/</guid><description>How to setup SSHFP records to verify SSH fingerprints What are SSHFP records and what problem are we trying to solve? NOTE: Feel free to skip this part if you know what SSHFP records are and want to get to the instructions
So, you might have noticed that every time you connect to a server over SSH you get a message like this:
The reasons for the message is that, unlike the CA system, the SSH protocol doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a centralised &amp;ldquo;root of trust&amp;rdquo; that forms the basis of authentication i.</description></item><item><title>Terraform and deduplication</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/monday-11th-october/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 22:51:06 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/monday-11th-october/</guid><description>Terraform and deduplication One of the issues I hit today was Terraform not picking up that I had declared an IAM policy for the same SNS topic in two different places. In fact it took me a long time to figure out what was going on as Terraform decided to use one of the policies and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand why the changes I was making were not being reflected at plan/apply time.</description></item><item><title>Learn Go with Tests book</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/thursday-7th-october/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 23:08:40 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/thursday-7th-october/</guid><description>Learning Go with Tests book About a year and a half ago, I started learning the Go programming language using this excellent Udemy course. This was good as a language introduction and allowed me to learn all the features of the language and how it worked under the hood. However, by itself I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel I got a massive amount from that course.
Then at some point (possibly through someone linking to it from the Go reddit) I came across the Learn Go with Tests boo.</description></item><item><title>What is Bazel?</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/saturday-2nd-october/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 22:28:48 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/saturday-2nd-october/</guid><description>What is Bazel? Recently I read an article from the Uber engineering team about how they are using Bazel on their Go monorepo. This prompted me to take a look at Bazel and what it does differently to other build systems.
Bazel is an open source build and test tool that originally came from Google. The main reasons why you might want to use it instead of the plethora of other build/test tools out there is that is optimised to do dependency management between libraries and services/binaries, regardless of language or framework.</description></item><item><title>Team Topologies Book Review</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-1st-october/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 23:17:55 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/friday-1st-october/</guid><description>Team Topologies I recently read the Team Topologies book, which I think was excellent. Specifically, for me, it did a great job of taking a lot of concepts around organising teams that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen startups and other fast moving companies use (i.e. a platform team as an internal product team) and formalised them into a framework.
While I don&amp;rsquo;t think anything in the book itself was particularly novel, the authors did a terrific job in distilling and simplifying the knowledge, by describing the problem, the technique to remedy the issue and why it &amp;ldquo;works&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Docker Container image scanning</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/wednesday-29th-sept/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 21:59:32 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/wednesday-29th-sept/</guid><description>Docker Container image scanning Some time ago, I wrote an article talking about the state of container scanning as it became clear that container images were going to have to be patched and the process was going to have to be managed just the same as we do for Linux boxes.
Recently, the question came up again at work after a colleague rightly balked at the integrated Azure Container Registry option (Azure Defender for ACR) costing ~$0.</description></item><item><title>The rise of K8s for infrastructure management</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/tuesday-28th-sept/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 22:01:55 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/tuesday-28th-sept/</guid><description>The rise of K8s for infrastructure management One of the typically overlooked aspects of moving to microservice architecture in general (and specificallyK8s for the purposes of this article) is the fact that each service &amp;ldquo;owns&amp;rdquo; its own datastore. Unless constrained by costs, this means a fully managed datastore instance (e.g. RDS). Once we accept that the service owns and manages the creation, upgrades etc&amp;hellip; of its own datastore, it then becomes logical to store the &amp;ldquo;infrastructure code&amp;rdquo; for this next to the application code (i.</description></item><item><title>My Second Post</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/my-second-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 22:36:10 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/my-second-post/</guid><description>Second Post Hi Again. Trying out the GitHub Actions triggers to rebuild and publish Hugo to the correct branch.</description></item><item><title>My first post</title><link>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 21:58:46 +1200</pubDate><guid>https://srdan.geek.nz/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>Hello World! Hi! This is my first blog post.</description></item></channel></rss>